Hey, hey,
hey, hey.
Well,
good morning everyone and welcome to the
Fiber Broadband Association's five for
breakfast. We're now in our 52nd and
final episode of 2025. Before we kick
off, I'd like to thank Wesco, the
platinum sponsor, Five for Breakfast.
You know, 2025 has been the best year in
the Fiber Broadband Association's
history. We saw our 20th straight
quarter of growth in revenue and
membership. And we just came off our
premier member meeting where we set our
direction for 20 26 and beyond. So
things could not be better. It's more
exciting than ever in our industry. And
you know, as we look to the next decade
and beyond, there just so much exciting
things we have before us. So, speaking
of 2026, the Fiber Broadband Association
will be kicking off our regional fiber
connect workshop in Oklahoma City on
Thursday, February 5th at the Okana
Resort. This is a brand new uh resort. I
think it's a Chickasaw Tribe that's um
hosting this and our focus will be on
tribal broadband. So, you're not going
to want to miss that. And last week on
five for breakfast, our guest was Mike
Render, the principal for RVA research
and our top strategic researcher for the
fiber broadband association and he
unveiled the 2025 fiber deployment
numbers. So Mike announced that the
fiber industry hit a new record for
fiber deployment in 2025 with 11.8
million homes passed this year. 11.8
million homes. That's 11% growth
year-over-year. Just amazing year we've
had. And we now have deployed fiber past
nearly 100 million homes in the US. It's
about 85 million um uh first passings
and then we have some second and third
passings. So if you miss that and you
want to hear all the latest stats um you
can come to our website and watch the
replay. It's just a great session. Today
our guests on Fire for Breakfast are
Jessica Ko, the controller at
Consolidated, and Evan Freeman, the vice
president of government affairs at EPB
um in Chattanooga. Jessica is the Fiber
Broadband Association's conference
committee chair for 2026 and Evan is the
vice chair for the Fiber Broadband
Association's board of directors. Um and
they're here to discuss the Fiber
Broadband Association's event reveal for
2026. You know, we just have an amazing
lineup of regional fiberconnect
workshops and our big Fiberconnect 2026
conference in Orlando in May. So,
Jessica Kok is an experienced financial
professional currently serving as
controller at Consolidated Business
Services LLC and she's focuses on
sustainable broadband models.
Previously, she held positions of
industry associations and external
affairs um and pro broadband program
manager at Kellix. and prior to that she
was the controller at and the business
office manager at PC Telecom. She holds
an MBA um from Turo University. Evan
Freeman joined EPB in Chattanooga in
2019 and serves as vice president in
government community relations. His
responsibilities include leading EP's
government relations and economic
development efforts to maintaining key
relationships with key government
partners on the local, state, and
national level. With over a decade of
experience in government relations, um
Evan has focused on public policy
efforts on community benefits and
coalition building. Prior to EPB, Evan
held various roles with former US
Senator Lamar Alexander where he
collaborated closely with state, local,
and federal stakeholders. So, Je Jess
Jessica and welcome. Jessica and Evan,
welcome. And for audience, please type
in your questions. Go. With that, I am
going to turn it over to our conference
leaders.
>> Hey Gary, thank thanks for uh having us
on. Um we're really excited to be on
another fiber for breakfast and and
right here uh right before the holidays.
>> Yeah. Well, happy holidays to everyone.
We're happy to uh jump right in and and
uh really excited to have have Jessica
as the as the conference chair this year
and um and look forward to to another
great event with with our with our best
fiber friends. um you know just kicking
off this this year uh our theme is light
years ahead and moving at the speed of
light and and why that that's important
um and why that that theme resonates
with us is like there's so much talk
about um you know the future of fiber
and and the technology but not only that
but there's been a lot of um other type
technology types that have been you know
introduced whether it's LEO or
traditional cable and other things that
have been talked about and and really is
put focusing on and doubling down on you
know if you're going to do um big things
in internet big things in technology
whereas AI quantum data centers others
it's just proven that that fiber is
light years ahead of all that technology
and and you know years and years and
years from now we're we're still going
to be using fiber to advance our our
community and so that's that's really
the theme and focus um on on it this
year just jumping in um for the program
uh just to talk a little bit about um
the conference and and how how we we
will go. Um as traditional, you know, we
we kick off with the FBA starter toolkit
on Sunday. Um we're going to have um
Latam with some of the pre-conference uh
sessions and then doing the very popular
marketing customer experience uh
conversation and then um on on Sunday
night of course um have a reception
which we'll get a little bit into um
later on in our presentation. Um but
then uh kicking off the the general
sessions on Monday and uh really excited
about some of the programming that we
have and and keeping popular things like
the seuite forum um adding precision a
program um streaming gaming just really
thinking about here are some
technologies and things uh that having
fiber access in your community. These
are things that you can benefit from and
um and really digging in deep into some
of those topics. um go going on to
Tuesday. One one big change that we're
doing on Tuesday is uh we usually open
Gary as you know with the general
session um on Tuesday, but this time
we're going to flip it and we're going
to have our breakout sessions on uh
Tuesday. We're going to continue to have
uh sort of the focus um set breakouts
being the teleaalth and broadband summit
um talking about hyperscalers data
center um bringing back the the popular
broadband policy symposium and then
we're we're actually going to open up
the expo hall um that that time before
we're having the general sessions
that'll start at one o'clock. Um, and
then another piece that we're going to
get into a little bit later in
presentation is the is the fiber awards
and banquet gala. And we're really
really really excited about that. And
then on Wednesday, we're going to have a
slide on this. But really excited about
the content on Wednesday and look
forward to talking to that talking about
that. But for the next slide, I'll kick
it over to Jessica to dig into the
general session programming.
>> Thanks, Evan. So I think um it's super
whoops
super exciting to um jump into the
general sessions and what attendees will
have to look forward to. Of course
because we are in Orlando we have taken
um a lot of themes from um popular
movies um to kind of connect those with
our content. So just a fun play on tying
the location to our event um you know
talking about connecting communities
from tip to tip. So, you know, having
representation from operators in Canada,
um, the US and, you know, our LATAM
chapter as well, and we're really
excited about that. Um, you know,
talking about early gig networks, you
know, building smart communities, um,
accelerating the network deployments,
you know, we've all been waiting on, you
know, bead funding to come through. And
so you know just talking about how we
accelerate accelerate those deployments
um and then managing those network
expansions and you know the established
network footprints you know how do we
um create more um ways to to pen
penetrate those markets and you know
create customer loyalty. Um, and then as
as as Evan touched on AI, quantum and
telecom, you know, how does the the
future generations of telecom what what
does that look like? Um, and then, you
know, kind of wrapping wrapping that up
with um just AI um what how that ties
into potentially, you know, data centers
and, you know, open compute projects.
Um, and then capacity and energy
requirements to scale AI. So, just
really a a good well-rounded um
general session programming lineup for
us.
And then Wednesday, um we are really
excited about the keynote speaker, um
Dr. Moio Kaku. Um that's going to be a
great kickoff for for Wednesday. Um and
then there will be, you know, a
follow-up fireside chat, um in addition
to his keynote. Um, I think this is
going to really create some some
excitement and some perspective um
around, you know, the opportunities that
lie ahead with AI and emerging tech. Um,
and just, you know, some additional
opportunities to hear from, you know, th
those that are familiar with the space,
that are excelling in this space. Um,
and a great opportunity for attendees
who are are looking at infusing this
more and more into their networks and
into their businesses. Um, you know,
getting to hear a perspective from, you
know, a leader in in this space will be
outstanding.
>> Evan, fiber family feud. Are you
excited?
>> I'm really excited about this. Um, so so
Gary, as you know, and I'm sure um as
our audience knows, we we you know,
Fiber Connect is is much more than than
just a conference. We're we're try to
make it an experience. And so, uh, last
year, um, you know, we did Hot Ones with
Sean Evans, which was really, really,
really cool. But this year, uh, we're
doing Fiber Family Feud. And so, we're
going to have, um, four teams. One team
will be, uh, full of state broadband
officers, uh, and the other three teams,
uh, will be sponsor teams, and so folks
have the opportunities to to sponsor and
and fill their teams up. We'll have
round one uh on the main stage uh which
will be the preliminary rounds and then
Tuesday afternoon in the general session
we'll have the uh family fee finals and
so it really exciting. Can't speak to um
who the who the host will be um but
we're going to have a lot of fun with
that and and so the theme will be all
fiber uh and industry related uh
questions and and answers and so it will
be relevant to to the crowd for sure.
Uh again the the live fiber for
breakfast um and we'll we'll be ho host
it and so I know Gary you you you love
those and and so again having that
content um out there and really been
able to do the fiber for breakfast live
at Fiber Connect. I started that a
couple years ago and and definitely have
have gotten great responses for that for
that content to continue.
Uh Jessica, I'll let you talk about
this, but we're we're really really
really excited about putting on um your
best dress um and and really the
entertainment that's going to be the
25th anniversary awards gayla, but I'll
let let Jessica talk about that.
>> Yeah, thanks Evan. We're super excited
about this event. This event is going to
be a little bit different than anything
we've done in the past. um it truly is
going to be a celebration of those in
innovators who are really leading the
way um for our industry, but it's also
going to be an opportunity to celebrate
um Fiber Broadband Association's
footprint in in that success, right? Um
so, you know, we're going to have a
great time to to network to to enjoy a
great dinner um to celebrate those um
who've been nominated and received
awards. Um, and then we're going to
close out the night with dueling pianos
and a dessert and just a lot of fun. Um,
and I think this is a great opportunity
for, you know, you think about being in
Orlando at the Gaylord, this is a great
opportunity for, you know, anybody who's
thinking about taking, you know, maybe
fellow attendees or customers to dinner.
consider buying a table at the you know
the awards gayla and joining us for not
only dinner and drinks and but also for
for entertainment and just a great time
of of networking with your peers. Um I
think this is you know also a great
opportunity where you know it's always a
lot of fun to get dressed up and you
know just do something um fun fun with
your your peers. Um and this is just
truly going to be a red carpet event. Um
and we want to really celebrate um those
in attendance, the award winners and the
fiber broadband association and how
we've all come together to um not only
create the successes that we've seen
today, but the vision that we have for
the future. So, um just really excited
about this event.
>> Yep. And and Jessica, do you have your
dress picked out yet or what you're
wearing? Is that
>> I have some contenders, but I haven't uh
solidified the finalist yet.
Well, we might get to see Gary in a bow
tie. I don't I don't know if that if
he's committed to that or not, but
>> Oh, that's easy for me. No problem. I
can borrow one from Tom.
>> Next up, just to talk a little bit about
the curated programs. Again, I mentioned
the seauite forum um and the broadband
policy
symposium. Bringing those two back. Uh
the seauite forum is again just an
opportunity for uh the seauite level
folks to have a content that's relevant
for them and and the curated programs
the idea behind it is that regardless of
who you are and what your job is in your
company there's something for you at
Fiber Connect and so uh the seuite form
opportunity uh with lounge space for you
to take calls do meetings and and things
like that that you need to do but also
having uh very um important and and
relevant um content uh throughout the
day as well. And so really excited to
have that back um as well as the
broadband policy symposium which is uh
attended for you know the the folks like
in in in my field the government
relations minds and and the really
policy focused folks to be able to hear
from important um policy uh leaders from
from DC on down to to the state and
local level. Um and so that that's a
pretty cool event. Um we're this year
we're adding uh teleaalth precision a uh
hyperscalers uh which are a big big
conversation right now in the fiber and
energy space across the country. And
then back to the the uh you know things
that you can also do with fiber that
dream a little stream and you know
talking about gaming and streaming
content uh and how that's changed the
industry and how fiber is very important
for that for that to continue to grow.
And I think one thing I might add, Evan,
there when you think about Fiber
Connect, um, you know, it's a one thing
that Fiber Connect really is a great
opportunity for is connecting with
others who you might be looking for, you
know, a partnership to solve a problem
within a community, right? And when I
think about these curated programs, you
know, there are a lot of nearly, you
know, every community is facing
teleaalth challenges. Um, precision a is
a big, you know, a big topic in the
rural space. And so, you know, a lot of
these speakers are going to be, you
know, professionals that are leading the
way in in these various areas. And so,
it's it's an opportunity for, you know,
providers and and attendees to connect
with those who are, you know, leading
the charge in in these various curated
programs. um and potentially get a
deeper dive on on insights as to how to
solve those those challenges that
they're facing um in their communities.
>> I think you're spot on, Jessica.
And then I, you know, I think that, you
know, another great thing about Fiber
Connect is, you know, the breakout
opportunities and and really being able
to select the content that um really
speaks to the needs of of your
organization
um you know, and and those have various
topics um on Monday and Tuesday um that
are oftentimes um panels, you know, so
you're getting to hear from various
perspectives on a particular topic. Um,
and those topics are going to include
deployment best practices, outside plant
considerations, service provider
ecosystems, data centers, open access,
fiber economics, local considerations,
and then FBA research readouts um on
Monday and then also include tribal
network expansion, marketing, MDU,
middle mile, and then again FBA uh
research on Tuesday.
Yep. And the the we're excited about the
the Expo Hall and and this year will be
no different. There there's another big
year. I know we're expecting over 300
exhibitors um in the Expo Hall. And so
it the energy is always great there and
and and it's always um awesome to get to
know and network uh with with a lot of
the the vendors there. But uh more
importantly, you know, it's an
opportunity. Last year we did the the
smart home um display. This year we're
we're focusing on the community, the
smart community. Um, and this is based
on what we've heard from from what folks
are interested in seeing. And so, um,
you know, what what does Fiverr bring to
the community? What what is a smart
community? And and you know, spanning
across all the the different um areas,
whether it's government, whether it's
healthcare, whether there's um industry,
transportation, um, all of those things.
And so, um, really excited to see how
this the this layout is going to be and
really a touch and feel experience for
folks to come through, um, and learn
about what applications are out there,
um, that that makes it a smart
community.
and keep it in line with with Expo Hall.
This will be um another element with the
Fiber Connect TV podcast um which will
be sort of traveling and and moving all
throughout the conference. Um but an
opportunity to to to catch folks and do
you know from interviewing the keynotes
to to key executives um if you have uh
different news with your company that
you want to share, talk about all the
different great things that our
committees do with producing FBA
research. um and and also talking with
uh policy and elected officials. And so
if you have a topic that that you want
to share and and um have interest there,
then I I encourage you to definitely
seek out the Fiber Connect podcast that
you can be a part of.
>> All right. Well, um guys, this is looks
like super exciting. I know that our
fiber connect conference is is is
bubbled up to be the best in the world.
It's the biggest fiber broadband
conference in the world. Um the thing I
love about it is the attention to detail
and um experience. You know, I don't
know of any other conference that has
professional musicians on segueing
between events and the um incredible
screens. Last year we had the big curved
gigantic screens AV's amazing and so
forth but also the so important to help
move the industry forward. So as Jessica
said you know that this is where we
engage. This is where everybody in the
ecosystem can get together to build
partnerships for transactions for um
really understanding the industry. But
you know let's talk about last year we
were lightening up. I know Evan, you had
your shoes that lit up. Tell us a little
bit about the theme this year.
>> Uh yeah, back back to the thing with
light years ahead. Um and you know,
coincidentally, we're in Orlando and and
there's Buzz Lightyear. Um that that
that's go that's pretty popular down
there. Again, just the the focus on the
the technology and how fiber is is
really moving our communities forward,
moving our country forward. And if if
we're going to be excel and be
competitive um you know globally then
our f our communities need access and
not just to broadband but what's next
you know with with all the things in AI
and quantum it it really is showing that
fiber is is futurep proof and you can
put layered technologies on top of this
fiber and really building that
infrastructure and so yes there's
there's all kind of technologies that
are being talked about and and things
that are saying that, you know, they can
provide just as good service as fiber.
Um that all that's continuously being
proven wrong and and really again the
focusing on fiber is light years ahead
of any technology um that that can
provide the information and data that we
need to go across this country.
So just on that theme um I know as many
of you guys know that Mitch Caku is my
favorite quantum physicist um of all
time. Don't tell Duncan. Duncan, he's my
second favorite. Um, but you know,
here's um inventor of string theory just
if you guys have seen him on the
Discovery Channel. But what I think, you
know, I love all his books. I read all
his books and what he does is he takes
very complex topics like quantum
networking and um just AI and all these
um technologies that could be very
complex and he's able to make them
relevant to the general public and I I
think that will be be great. But can you
talk a little bit about where we are in
the fiber industry, you know, as far as,
you know, we've got 100 million homes
passed now and kind of what, you know,
especially Evan as you know, in the
utility space, but how what's going to
be our future as leveraging fiber to
enable these new technologies?
>> Yeah, Gary, and I'm glad um you brought
that up and and I'm definitely a Dr. Pu
fan and part of me um loves watching
Ancient Aliens which which he's he's a
regular on so throw that plug out. But
um as far as the the technology um and
what's been enabled with fiber is as as
AI um you know because of AI and and all
the data that's been collected and um
having to be distributed then you know
you need a couple things lots of energy
and lots of um capacity to to move data
quickly and that's where um fiber is
really important to have and so these
hyperscalers and and um all of the big
players you know whether it's your
Google's Microsofts all those folks that
are in the data I mean in the data
center space fiber is very important and
high capacity fiber is very important
for for the technology to be able to
develop and move and then moving on to
to quantum networking um you know at EPB
we've been been working in quantum for
since 2016
and and seeing the the capabilities
whether it's uh from a security cyber
security application being able detect
um protect the electric grid with on
over to um you know the the vast amounts
of data that needs to be optimized in
the future. If you think about um all
the things that are are becoming smart.
So, you know, not only smart home and
community, but autonomous vehicles, um,
all these things that are going to be
communicating. Um, so one, you're going
to need fast broadband for it to be
successful. Um, and you're going to need
fiber back hall for that to be
successful, but then moving that that
vast amounts of data like quantum
technology is going to be very important
in managing that and optimizing that.
And so, how how do you build a efficient
transportation network? how do you
optimize all the healthcare data? Um
finance and banking um have huge
interest in the cyber security and
protection um aspects of it. And so it
really spans across every industry and
is going to really re revolutionize
every industry. And so having fiber in
your community not only gets you
broadband access today, but it it really
gives the community an opportunity to
participate in what's going to be a a
groundbreaking technology in quantum
once it once it hits his moment.
You know, I I think it's gonna be
awesome conference. So, Jessica, you
know, this year you are the big cheese
as far as the conference chair and also
that means a lot of road work too
because you're going to be going around
the country um leading all our regional
fiber connects. Can you talk a little
bit about what you see on the regional
fiberconnects and um you know what will
be people can expect for 2026?
>> Sure, Gary. I think the great thing that
just continues to stand out about the
regionals is it's a very um great
opportunity for
all of those who have their hands in you
know deploying fiber networks and you
know the the future applications that
you know tie to those networks. These
regionals provide an outstanding
opportunity for for all those people to
come together in one room um share share
their experience, share their knowledge,
connect with, you know, other operators,
other solution providers who really
continue to help us achieve the goal of
goal of being light years ahead, right?
and and we do that regionally so that
people from all over the country can can
attend these can participate can share
can be learners of um and and just
really have that networking opportunity.
I mean we talk about building networks
um whe you know and with fiber but we
also need networks of people right to to
share knowledge to share experience um
and to really continue to move that dial
forward because as we as you mentioned
the the top of this um conversation
today you know we continue to set
records in terms of deployment but you
know what's going to keep those networks
going what's going to keep them relevant
are going to be the applications you
know and the opportunities that
communities achieve because of those
networks. And you know, I just think
these these regionals showcase,
you know, regionally what's happening,
what's important, what the challenges
are. And, you know, the broad fiber
broadband association is just continuing
to work and partner um across the
country to bring solutions that continue
to drive us forward.
Well, I tell you what. Um, well, maybe
you guys can mention just our membership
has been absolutely phenomenal on what
didn't we have a record on submissions
for speaker on during the call for
speakers? What what did that end up? Can
you talk a little bit about the process?
>> Yeah, so we had over 300 submissions and
this year we had more operator
submissions than we've had in in years
prior and I think that just speaks um
all by itself, right? when you have a
record number of operators wanting to
come to Fiber Connect to not only be an
active participant but to share their
experience on you know on our stages. Um
that tells me that we're we're picking
relevant topics. Um we are picking
relevant strategies and we're being
successful in connecting people um
across the country um with ways and
thoughts and leadership that are
continuing to drive their vision
forward.
>> Well, congratulations. you guys have
just done a phenomenal job on um really
making our conference very relevant as
Jessica says and just engaging and so
we're just incredibly excited about um
2026. I mean, we will have the biggest
and best conference in the world. And
I'm just excited, not only just our
regionals, but also, you know, in
February 24th and 25th, our policy
summit in Washington DC. In the fall,
we'll be at Fiberday in the Hill. Um,
our premier member meeting next year in
December will be in Isa Marada back at
the Chica Lodge. Um, it just so many
amazing things. Um, I'm really excited
about having all our Latin American
members coming and join us for the Latin
America workshop at in Orlando in May.
So, um, it's going to be an incredible
year. And then I really appreciate you
guys joining us today. Jessica, Evan,
thanks again. We appreciate everything
you've done to really make our events so
engaging and world class. And I
>> look forward to getting back together
next Wednesday, everybody. We're going
to have Ash Brown from Atran, our new um
2026 Fiber Broadband Association board
of directors chairwoman, and she is
going to discuss our plans, policies,
and programs for 2026. So, you're not
going to want to miss. So, I hope
everybody enjoys their Christmas Eve,
has a wonderful Christmas and holiday,
New Year's, and we'll be back off um in
the beginning of the year racing towards
um Oklahoma City and and well, I think
the first thing we do is we're going to
have our big policy summit with NTI and
then race off to um Oklahoma City for
our tribal broadband meetings. But um
thanks again and we'll see you guys in
the new year.